# Erick Clark

# **User Experience Designer**

www.erickclark.com • erickclark@gmail.com • 512-481-2368

# **Summary**

I'm a seasoned UX and UI designer with experience working for a mix of companies including design agencies, large corporations and startups. I've designed SaaS and enterprise web applications and have a lot of experience designing easy-to-use products that require complex workflow.

#### **Skills**

UX Design Agile Methodologies Usability Testing
UI Design Data Visualization Prototyping
Mobile Design Design Systems HTML & CSS

User Research Design Thinking Sketch, Adobe XD, Figma

#### **Education**

Graduated with a BFA in Design from the University of Texas at Austin.

#### **Certifications**

UX Certification with a specialty in UX Management from the Nielsen Norman Group - ID 1038106

# **Experience**

Senior UX Designer - InfoBlox

Nov 2020 - Present

As a member of Infoblox's distributed UX team, I work with product managers, software engineers and stakeholders on InfoBlox's cloud based network administration and security products.

- Work in a user centered process as a UX generalist, doing UX research and UX design
- Own the user experience of InfoBlox's newest product, currently under development
- Own web analytics of the company's SaaS products

#### **Contract UX Lead - Thales Gemalto**

Sept 2018 - Dec 2019

As a part of Thales Gemalto's Identity and Access Management team, I worked with a distributed team of product managers, designers and developers on the company's enterprise network security SaaS products.

- Acted as scrum master for the UX Team
- Designed new and updated features for Thales Gemalto's identity and access management software
- Developed and updated the team's design system
- Improved the teams UX processes
- Conducted user interviews and tests

#### **Contract Senior UX Architect - Dell**

Nov 2017 - Feb 2018

I worked as part of the Dell Services IT UX team to improve the ease of use of Dell's internal support tools.

- Conducted research by interviewing stakeholders and subject-matter experts.
- Documented existing products by creating process flows
- Created clickable wireframes to demonstrate design concepts and for user testing

# **UX Architect & Product Design Manager - Datafiniti**

May 2012 – Nov 2017

Datafiniti is a start-up that data-mines the web. The company crawls and scrapes the web for specific types of data and compiles it into a massive database. As the company's in-house designer, I reported to the Chief Executive Officer and took on many duties including UX design lead and product owner.

- Acted as scrum master and team lead for the company's web product team
- Defined the user experience and strategic vision for the company's database search interface
- Designed the interface for the company's web crawling software
- Conducted user tests, interviewed customers and evaluated competing products

# **User Experience Architect - Adometry**

Apr 2010 – May 2012

Adometry, acquired by Google in 2014, provided analysis of online advertising data. I worked with the executive staff, data scientists and developers as the company's in-house UX architect and designer.

- Worked with product managers and data scientists to define the strategic vision of the company's web based software
- Created wireframes, low and high fidelity prototypes to demonstrate design concepts
- Designed the web interface for the company's advertising attribution SaaS software
- Improved the ease of use of the company's click fraud detection and monitoring SaaS software

# Senior Interaction Designer - D&B Hoover's Inc.

Sept 2007 – Apr 2010

As a part of D&B Hoover's internal design team, I worked on several projects related to the company's subscription service.

- Improved the ease of use of the company's database search tool (Lead Builder)
- Created wireframes, low and high fidelity prototypes to demonstrate design concepts
- Worked on a complete redesign of the company's subscription service
- Collaborated with product managers to define and design features
- Worked with usability testers to gain insights into user behavior

#### **Other Experience**

Earlier in my career I was employed by Frog Design and Razorfish, and worked as a freelance UX and visual designer

- Collaborated with remote teams across locations, both domestic and international
- Worked with clients to determine design requirements for projects
- Led the design process from concept to implementation
- Worked on both business facing and consumer facing websites and web applications
- Worked on projects from small start-ups to Fortune 100 companies